Contact EMAIL: yoyo927@gmail.com

NATIONALITY:

Taiwan

**Information** 

**Summary** 

My main interest is in HCI and interaction design. I am especially interested in two topics. The first one is how new digital tools induce subtle behavior change and thus unknowingly reshape our perception, cognition, and the way we perceive the world. The second one, influenced by my work experience, lies in home robot's interaction and communication that conveys emotion and personality.

## **Education**

2013-2014

## Master of Science, Human-Computer Interaction with Ergonomics

University College London (UCL), London, UK

 Dissertation: Seeing More or Less? An In-the-Wild Study Comparing How Pedestrians Use Smartphone Versus Paper Maps

Advisor: Professor Yvonne Rogers

\* 2013-14 Distinction Projects

 Solid training in human centered design practice, usability testing, interface design, and ergonomic methodologies.

2008-2011

Bachelor of Science, Psychology, National Taiwan University (NTU), Taipei, Taiwan

• Intensive training in cognitive psychology, sensation and perception, experimental design, psychological testing, and statistics.

2007-2011

Bachelor of Art, Industrial Design, Shih-Chien University, Taipei, Taiwan

- Strong skills for the whole iterative design process: ideation, sketching, and lowand high-fidelity prototyping.
- Competent in Adobe creative suite and 3D-modeling software.

**Publications** 

Hou, T.Y., Rogers, Y., (2016). Seeing More or Less? An In-the-Wild Study Comparing How Pedestrians Use Smartphone Versus Paper Maps. In preparation.

Chang, Y.C., Hou, T.Y., Lu, C.H. (2012). *Investigating human performance on large touchscreen: the effect of tilt angle, icon location and icon size*. Paper presented at Order in Disorder: USC International Design Theory and Practice Conference, Taipei, Taiwan.

## **Academic Experience**

2016	Workshop speaker and facilitator, Workshop: The look of behavior design, Soochow
	University, Taipei, Taiwan
2012	Invited instructor, E-commerce Conference on User Experience Research and Design,

Taipei, Taiwan

2012-2013 Research Assistant, Design Psychology Lab, Shih-Chien University, Taipei, Taiwan

- Investigated user behavior with new-generation large touchscreen device with ASUS design research team.
- Prepared design thinking lessons suitable for design school students.

2011-2013

**Teaching Assistant,** for *Psychology in Human Factors and Design* by Professor Yeh, Yei-Yu, National Taiwan University (NTU), Taipei, Taiwan

• Introduced HCI knowledge and practical prototyping techniques.

## **Work Experience**

2015-2016

UX Designer, ASUS Design Center, ASUSTeK Computer Inc., Taipei, Taiwan

- Main UX designer for Zenbo (Asus home robot), including system architecture and interaction, voice interface, emotion expression through voice and sound, posture and movement design, and the specifications and interaction of 11 native apps.
- The writer of *Design Guideline for Zenbo*, the official document for developers.
- Project owner of Asus mobile phone's 8 apps, including Phone, Message, Contact,
  Music, Calendar and To-do lists. Project owner of Zenwatch's instant message app.

2013, 2014

Interaction Designer, Kuchi Co. Ltd., Taipei, Taiwan

Conducted user studies, and accordingly created wireframes and prototypes.

2007-2013

Chief Design Officer, Vox Nativa Music Association, Nantou, Taiwan

Led all the design works from visual identity to movie posters and album arts

**Selected Design** 

Biology (high school textbook), KangSi Cultural Co. Ltd., 2010-2013

Works

National Day Brochure, Office of the President, Taiwan, 2011

Movie poster for Award winning "Let the wind carry me", Yonder Film, 2010

Official Campus Map, National Taiwan University, 2006

**Funding** 

Government Scholarship for Studying Abroad, Ministry of Education, Taiwan, 2016

• In process. High possibility of getting partial tuition covered (up to 90,000, for 3 years) and living stipend (17,000~20,000 per year).

**Test Scores** 

**GRE** Verbal: 166 (96%), Quantitative: 170 (99%)

**TOEFL** 111 (READING: 30, LISTENING: 29, SPEAKING: 24, WRITING: 28) **IELTS** 8.0 (READING: 9.0, LISTENING: 8.5, SPEAKING: 7.5 WRITING: 7.5)

**Skills** 

**IT (design)** Adobe creative suite (professional level in Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, Aftereffect, Flash, Audition), AutoCAD, Microsoft Visio, Balsamiq.

IT (statistics) SAS

Language: Native: Chinese Mandarin, Taiwanese

Fluent: English Intermediate: Japanese

Reference upon request